Your Highness
Милорд
Be careful in all matters
Милорд будь осторожен во всём
Don't worry
Не волнуйся я знаю что делаю
Stop swaying
Не махай
It's distracting
глаза режет
Or perhaps, Your Excellency
Может вы старик
Could pay someone to perform a ritual
заплатите комунибудь чтобы устроили обряд
To make Yu Gong appear from the Imperial City Guard
и вытащили Юй Гуна из тюремной канцелярии
Enough, both of you
Хватит болтать оба
Your Highness
Ваше Высочество
Tell us
Расскажи
About that day
о том что произошло в тот день
Yu Gong, Chancellor of the Imperial Academy
Юй Гун надзиратель Академии Гоцзицзянь
Was like a teacher to me
наполовину мой учитель
That day
Этим стихом
He introduced his disciples to me
он представил мне своих учеников
After several rounds of wine
после нескольких чаш вина
Your Highness
Ваше Высочество
He got carried away
Когда он вдохновлён
Composed a sentimental poem
сочинил жалкое стихотворение
Never forget
не забывайте
The resolve to recover our divine land
желание вернуть земли Китая
Now
сейчас
His poem
его стихотворение
Has been framed by my elder brother and the Chen family
был оклеветан старшим братом и родом Чэнь
As inciting rebellion
это подстрекательство к мятежу
This is a disaster
наделал больших бед
What exactly did Yu Gong say?
А что же всётаки сказал Юй Гун
What he wrote doesn't matter
Не важно что он написал
Since
Раз так
Your Highness was present that day
В тот день Ваше Высочество тоже был там
Prince of Ning and the Chen family
Принц Нин и род Чэнь
Must be trying to drag Your Highness into this
наверняка хотят втянуть в это дело Ваше Высочество
The urgent matter
Первостепенно
Is to eliminate all those
убрать всех свидетелей с того дня
Who were present at the tavern that day
всех присутствующих казнить
To cut ties with Yu Gong
Связь с Юй Гуном разорвана
And ensure this matter
Так мы гарантируем
Does not touch you at all
что дело не коснётся вас Ваше Высочество
Minister Xie speaks so casually
Министр Се одним словом
How many must die?
сколько людей придется убить
Your Highness
Ваше Высочество
Yu Gong has great prestige
Юй Гун в Академии
In the Imperial Academy
и среди народа
And among the people
пользуется большим уважением
He has also recommended many talents to Your Highness
рекомендовал Вам многих талантливых людей
If Your Highness abandons him
Если Вы его бросите
What will scholars think?
что подумают ученые по всей стране
Moreover
Более того
If you don't protect your own
если своих не защищаете
In the future
В будущем
Which court official
все чиновники при дворе
Would dare serve Your Highness
кто осмелится за Вас
With wholehearted loyalty?
служить преданно
A benevolent ruler cannot stand in troubled times
Милосердным правителем в смутные времена не стать
Your Highness aims to recover the northern lost lands
Вы стремитесь вернуть северные земли
If you hesitate for one subordinate
если изза одного подчиненного будете колебаться
And create a rift with His Majesty
возникнет конфликт с императором
Then
Тогда
That would be a greater loss
это будет невыгодно
Of course
Конечно
How to decide
решать Вам
Is up to Your Highness
зависит от решения Вашего Высочества